{"question": "A 23-year-old black male presents to a psychiatrist for evaluation of situational anxiety. He reports that he recently started a new job that involves regular public speaking and is very stressed before every public speaking event. He describes developing a rapid heart rate and diaphoresis that interferes with his ability to speak well. He has no past medical history and takes no medications. He does not smoke or drink alcohol. His temperature is 98.6°F (37°C), blood pressure is 110/65 mmHg, pulse is 85/min, and respirations are 17/min. On exam, he is well-appearing and appropriately conversational. He is alert and fully oriented. The male is prescribed propranolol to take before major public speaking events. Which of the following physiologic changes will occur when the male takes this medication?", "options": {"A": "Decreased cardiac output and decreased peripheral resistance", "B": "Decreased cardiac output and increased peripheral resistance", "C": "Increased cardiac output and decreased peripheral resistance", "D": "Increased cardiac output and increased peripheral resistance"}, "answer": "Decreased cardiac output and increased peripheral resistance", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "An 18-year-old black male presents to the emergency room smelling quite heavily of alcohol and is unconscious. A blood test reveals severe hypoglycemic and ketoacidemia. A previous medical history states that he does not have diabetes. The metabolism of ethanol in this patient's hepatocytes resulted in an increase of the [NADH]/[NAD+] ratio. Which of the following reaction is favored under this condition?", "options": {"A": "Pyruvate to acetyl-CoA", "B": "Citrate to isocitrate", "C": "Oxaloacetate to malate", "D": "Oxaloacetate to phosphoenolpyruvate"}, "answer": "Oxaloacetate to malate", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 58-year-old black male with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and hypertension comes to the physician because of shortness of breath 3 days after starting propranolol. His temperature is 36.7°C (98.1°F), pulse is 64/min, respirations are 20/min, and blood pressure is 138/88 mm Hg. Auscultation of the lungs shows diffuse expiratory wheezes. In addition to discontinuing the propranolol, which of the following drugs should be administered?", "options": {"A": "Albuterol", "B": "Prednisone", "C": "Tiotropium bromide", "D": "Theophylline"}, "answer": "Albuterol", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 24-year-old black male is brought into the emergency room after being retrieved by firefighters from a burning building. The male is responding coherently to questions but reports pain secondary to a burn on his leg. He states he also has a headache and feels dizzy. His temperature is 98.5°F (36.9°C), blood pressure is 129/66 mmHg, pulse is 126/min, respirations are 14/min, and oxygen saturation is 99% on room air. Physical exam is notable for a confused young male with dry and flushed skin. Cardiopulmonary exam reveals a normal S1 and S2 as well as clear breath sounds bilaterally. The patient's neurological exam is within normal limits. Towards the end of his exam, the male begins vomiting. Dermatologic exam reveals a superficial burn covering 1% of the patient's body over his right leg. Which of the following is the best next step in management for this patient?", "options": {"A": "100% oxygen", "B": "Hydroxocobalamin", "C": "Normal saline", "D": "Ondansetron"}, "answer": "100% oxygen", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 33-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with joint pain. He states that since yesterday he has had joint pain, and today he noticed a rash. The male does not have a significant past medical history. The male smokes cigars, drinks 1 to 4 drinks per day, is sexually active, and uses cocaine occasionally. His temperature is 101°F (38.3°C), blood pressure is 125/65 mmHg, pulse is 80/min, respirations are 14/min, and oxygen saturation is 98% on room air. Physical exam reveals pustular skin lesions and an inflamed and painful right knee that is warm to the touch. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment for the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Cefixime and azithromycin", "B": "Ceftriaxone", "C": "Ceftriaxone and vancomycin", "D": "Piperacillin and tazobactam"}, "answer": "Cefixime and azithromycin", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 42-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department because of several episodes of black, tarlike stool and lightheadedness over the past couple of days. He underwent an appendectomy at the age of 16. He has hypertension and tension headaches. He drinks 4 beers daily. Current medications include amlodipine and naproxen. His temperature is 36.7°C (98°F), pulse is 100/min, and his blood pressure is 100/70 mm Hg. The lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally. The abdomen is soft, nondistended, and nontender. The liver is palpated 3 cm below the right costal margin. His hemoglobin concentration is 10 g/dL. Intravenous fluid resuscitation has begun. An esophagogastroduodenoscopy is performed, which does not show bleeding. Which of the following is the most appropriate next step in management?", "options": {"A": "Double-balloon enteroscopy", "B": "Colonoscopy", "C": "Laparotomy", "D": "Angiography\n"}, "answer": "Colonoscopy", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 73-year-old black male is brought to his family practitioner by his daughter with the complaints of a spinning sensation for the past 4 weeks. He says that the room appears to be continuously spinning. This has progressively worsened over the last 4 weeks to the point that he has become bed bound and cannot walk without support. These spinning sensations are present throughout the day and do not change with position. They are associated with nausea and vomiting. He denies ear pain, ear discharge, ringing in the ear, hearing disturbances, ear fullness, head trauma, fever, or recent flu-like illness. He has a blood pressure of 133/80 mm Hg, heart rate of 80/min, respiratory rate of 12/min, and temperature of 36.7°C (98.2°F). His extraocular eye movements are normal in all directions, but a vertical nystagmus is present that does not disappear despite repetitive testing. Hearing tests are within normal limits. What is the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Acute labyrinthitis", "B": "Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo", "C": "Cerebellar tumor", "D": "Meniere's disease"}, "answer": "Cerebellar tumor", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 35-year-old black male presents to the dermatologist with a new skin rash. The male has noticed new bumps on his arm over the past 1 month. The bumps are about 0.5 cm in diameter and are filled with a clear fluid. They extend on both arms but are not in his mouth or torso. The lesions do not pop with pressure but remain tense. His skin does not slough off with rubbing. The male denies any other symptoms including joint pain or fever. The male has no other medical history. The patient's condition is most likely caused by antibodies against which of the following compounds?", "options": {"A": "Desmoglein", "B": "Hemidesmosomes", "C": "Double-stranded DNA", "D": "U1 ribonucleotide polypeptide"}, "answer": "Hemidesmosomes", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 70-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department by staff of the group home where he resides because of fever, a productive cough, and blood-tinged sputum for 2 days. The staff report that he developed myalgia, headache, and rhinorrhea 7 days ago, which improved initially before worsening again. He has hypertension and Alzheimer disease. Current medications include enalapril and donepezil. On arrival, he is obtunded. His temperature is 39.8°C (103.6°F), pulse is 120/min, respirations are 22/min and shallow, and blood pressure is 100/60 mm Hg. Pulse oximetry on 10 L/min of oxygen via nasal cannula shows an oxygen saturation of 92%. Examination shows scattered crackles and rhonchi throughout both lung fields. An x-ray of the chest shows bilateral lung opacities and multiple small, thin-walled cystic spaces within the basal pulmonary parenchyma. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient's current condition?", "options": {"A": "Infection with Staphylococcus aureus", "B": "Infection with Aspergillus fumigatus", "C": "Foreign body aspiration", "D": "Granulomatosis with polyangiitis"}, "answer": "Infection with Staphylococcus aureus", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 43-year-old black male presents to a new primary care physician complaining of anxiety. He has been worrying non-stop recently about the possibility that his partner will lose their job as a teacher. His partner, who is present, assures the physician that their job is entirely secure and states that he has \"fretted\" for their entire marriage, though the exact topic causing his anxiety varies over time. He also worries excessively about everyday tasks, such as whether he will catch the train on time and whether their house in Southern California is sufficiently earthquake-proof. He has no way to overcome these worries. He endorses other symptoms including poor sleep (associated with racing thoughts about his various worries), fatigue, and impaired concentration at work, all of which have been present for at least the past year. His vital signs are within normal limits and there are no abnormalities on physical exam. What is the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Social phobia", "B": "Agoraphobia", "C": "Posttraumatic stress disorder", "D": "Generalized anxiety disorder"}, "answer": "Generalized anxiety disorder", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 43-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department because of a fever, cough, pleuritic chest pain, and dyspnea. Two days ago, he returned from a construction site along the Mississippi River. Abdominal examination shows a palpable spleen. An x-ray of the chest shows diffuse reticulonodular infiltrates. Therapy with a drug that binds ergosterol is initiated. This male is most likely to experience which of the following adverse effects?", "options": {"A": "Hypomagnesemia", "B": "Histamine release", "C": "Leukopenia", "D": "Cytochrome P450 induction"}, "answer": "Hypomagnesemia", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 48-year-old black male presents to the physician with a cough with expectoration and breathlessness on exertion for the last 4 years. There is no history of any other medical conditions. He has been a smoker for the last 10 years. He recently immigrated from a developing country and his immunization status is unknown. After a complete physical examination of the patient, the physician orders a chest radiogram which shows increased bronchovascular markings and flattening of the diaphragm. His spirometry findings include an FEV1 of 82% of predicted, which increases to 88% of predicted at 15 minutes after the administration of inhaled albuterol. The FEV1/FVC ratio is 0.66. The physician explains the diagnosis to the male and emphasizes the importance of smoking cessation. He also offers them specific vaccinations. However, the male mentions that he does not have medical insurance and due to his poor financial situation, he can afford only 1 of the suggested vaccines. In such a situation, which of the following vaccines should definitely be recommended to this patient?", "options": {"A": "23-valent pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine", "B": "Haemophilus influenzae type b vaccine", "C": "Influenza vaccine", "D": "Pertussis vaccine"}, "answer": "Influenza vaccine", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 75-year-old black male is brought to the emergency room by his daughter due to slurred speech and a drooping eyelid on the right side. This morning, he had difficulty eating his breakfast and immediately called his daughter for help. He says that his voice also seems different. His temperature is 99°F (37.2°C), blood pressure is 120/78 mmHg, pulse is 90/min, respirations are 21/min, and pulse oximetry is 98% on room air. On physical exam, he is oriented to time and place. There is right-sided nystagmus and he has difficulty with point-to-point movement. Where is the lesion responsible for his symptoms most likely located?", "options": {"A": "Posterior inferior cerebellar artery", "B": "Anterior cerebral artery", "C": "Anterior inferior cerebellar artery", "D": "Basilar artery"}, "answer": "Posterior inferior cerebellar artery", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 32-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician with complaints of chronic headaches that have developed and increased in frequency and severity over the last several months. Additionally, the male has noted he has been less coordinated over the last few weeks, stumbling and tripping often when he is walking. Physical examination is significant for notably reduced hand grip strength bilaterally as well as decreased pain and temperature sensation along the upper back and down both arms to the hands. A referral to the appropriate specialist is made, and an MRI of the brain and neck is obtained. Results of the MRI are show in Figures A and B. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Arnold-Chiari malformation type 1", "B": "Arnold-Chiari malformation type 2", "C": "Arnold-Chiari malformation type 3", "D": "Arnold-Chiari malformation type 4"}, "answer": "Arnold-Chiari malformation type 1", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 25-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department by his partner for abdominal pain. The partner answers all questions posed to the male by the physician. Throughout the interview, the male makes very little eye contact with the physician. His partner asks the physician to prescribe \"something for his abdominal pain\" so that they can return home. Examination of the male shows mild bruising in the left infraorbital area and a right periorbital hematoma. When asked about his injuries, he quietly states that he fell while walking down the stairwell of his apartment complex. The partner reluctantly leaves the examination room when asked to by the physician. While alone with the physician, the male admits that his partner is responsible for his injuries. Which of the following immediate responses by the physician is most appropriate?", "options": {"A": "May I add some information about local domestic violence agencies to your discharge records?", "B": "Do you feel safe leaving the emergency department?", "C": "How often has your partner physically hurt you in the past?", "D": "May I ask your partner to join us so we can talk about this matter together?"}, "answer": "Do you feel safe leaving the emergency department?", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 29-year-old black male comes to the physician because of a 4-month history of fever, progressive shortness of breath, and a dry cough. During this time, he has also had a 5-kg (11-lb) weight loss. Two months ago, he was in Kenya for several weeks to visit his family. Physical examination shows fine crackles and wheezing over both lung fields. His serum calcium concentration is 11.8 mg/dL. An x-ray of the chest shows reticular opacities in both lungs and bilateral hilar lymphadenopathy. Which of the following is the most likely underlying mechanism of this condition?", "options": {"A": "Necrotizing inflammation", "B": "Granulomatous inflammation", "C": "Monoclonal plasma cell production", "D": "Neoplastic transformation\n"}, "answer": "Granulomatous inflammation", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male is brought to the physician after passing out at home. His partner reports that he suddenly lost consciousness for approximately 30 seconds while shoveling snow in the driveway. Immediately before the episode, he felt light-headed and short of breath. Two months ago, he experienced a similar episode while running in his yard with his children. He has no history of serious illness. His father died of sudden cardiac death at the age of 44 years. Vital signs are within normal limits. Cardiac examination shows a systolic ejection murmur best heard along the left sternal border that decreases with hand grip. The remainder of the examination shows no abnormalities. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Septal myectomy", "B": "Amlodipine", "C": "Cardiac pacemaker", "D": "Metoprolol"}, "answer": "Metoprolol", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 50-year-old black male visits his primary care physician with skin lesions on his knees and elbows. He reports joint pain, and physical examination reveals severe swelling of the fingers on both hands. Tests for serum rheumatoid factor are negative. Which of the following pairs of adjectives most likely characterize the patient's skin lesions:", "options": {"A": "Honey-colored, crusting", "B": "Irregular, depigmented", "C": "Silver, scaly", "D": "Non-blanching, hemorrhagic"}, "answer": "Silver, scaly", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A healthy 32-year-old black male enrolls in a study investigating kidney function. His renal plasma flow (RPF) is 600 mL/min. He is administered an intravenous substance that does not undergo tubular reabsorption. The following sets of measurements are taken every 10 minutes: Plasma concentration of substance Excretion rate of substance Set 1 0.1 mg/mL 60 mg/min Set 2 0.15 mg/mL 90 mg/min Set 3 0.2 mg/mL 104 mg/min Set 4 0.25 mg/mL 110 mg/min Set 5 0.3 mg/mL 116 mg/min This male was most likely administered which of the following substances?", "options": {"A": "Cystatin C", "B": "Glucose", "C": "Para-aminohippurate", "D": "Iohexol"}, "answer": "Para-aminohippurate", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 29-year-old black male presents to his primary care provider for a normal check-up at the prompting of his mother. When asked how he is doing, he replies that he feels depressed. Upon further questioning, he states that he feels \"worthless\" now that his ex-partner left them 2 days ago. He has been sitting in their bed all day trying to call them but he is not answering his calls. He says that he will never find another person like them and feels like he should just \"disappear\" rather than continue living without them. He also reports that he can hear their voice when they are not around, especially at night before he goes to bed. He denies having any other friends and has some social anxiety, particularly in large groups of people. A review of his medical record indicates that he has endured several episodes of verbal and physical abuse from his prior relationships which he suggested \"were all his fault.\" He has had 4 prior serious relationships and reports that he has not been single for more than a few days in the last 10 years. On exam, he is unkempt with poor self-care. This patient's history is most consistent with which of the following conditions?", "options": {"A": "Avoidant personality disorder", "B": "Dependent personality disorder", "C": "Histrionic personality disorder", "D": "Paranoid personality disorder"}, "answer": "Dependent personality disorder", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 34-year-old black male presents with sudden onset flank pain for the past day. He describes the pain as intermittent and radiating to his groin. He denies any similar symptoms in the past. No significant past medical history. The male currently does not take any medications. Family history is significant for his mother who died of a pancreatic tumor at the age of 53. Laboratory analysis reveals: Serum calcium 12 mg/dL Serum phosphorus 2.2 mg/dL Serum parathyroid hormone 105 pg/mL Which of the following mutated gene products is most likely causing this patient's symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Receptor tyrosine kinase", "B": "Cytokine receptor", "C": "Threonine kinase", "D": "Menin"}, "answer": "Menin", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 56-year-old black male reports a history of recurrent dental caries. The bacteria causing this patient's dental problems most likely exhibits which of the following properties?", "options": {"A": "Inhibition of growth on optochin sensitivity test", "B": "Production of dextrans from glucose", "C": "Presence of catalase enzyme", "D": "Soluble in bile"}, "answer": "Production of dextrans from glucose", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with altered mental status. His parents found them in his room surrounded by pill bottles, alcohol, and illicit drugs 10 minutes ago and promptly brought them in. He was unconscious with lacerations on his wrists. The male has a past medical history of depression, fibromyalgia, and multiple suicide attempts. Physical exam is notable for a somnolent young male who responds to questions but is non-compliant in describing the history. He is currently vomiting and his gait seems ataxic. Initial laboratory values are unremarkable. An arterial blood gas analysis reveals the following findings. Arterial blood gas pH: 7.50 pO2: 105 mmHg pCO2: 20 mmHg Bicarbonate: 24 mEq/L Which of the following is the most likely intoxication in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Acetaminophen", "B": "Amitriptyline", "C": "Aspirin", "D": "Ethylene glycol"}, "answer": "Aspirin", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 17-year-old black male is presented to the clinic by his mom for hair loss. Both the male and his mom have noted random patches of hair loss across the male scalp, eyebrows, and eyelashes, 1st appearing several months ago. The male has noticed no other symptoms, though the spots of hair loss are sometimes sore. On further questioning, the male shares that he has been very stressed lately about getting good grades and applying to colleges. He knows he needs to do well on all of his homework in order to get into a good college, so he has sometimes had to stay up late into the night to rewrite his homework over and over again so that they are 'absolutely perfect'. The physical exam shows an anxious-appearing, somewhat quiet There is diffuse hair loss and thinning across his scalp, with many different hair shafts of different lengths. There is no discernible pattern to the hair loss. Which of the following is the best treatment for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Cognitive-behavioral therapy", "B": "Intralesional steroids", "C": "Oral griseofulvin", "D": "Systemic steroids"}, "answer": "Cognitive-behavioral therapy", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 49-year-old black male visits the emergency department with the acute onset of severe shortness of breath. He also reports right-sided calf pain that developed after a 22-hour flight from Beijing to Los Angeles, and that, several hours after he felt pain in his calf, he began to have trouble breathing. Currently, his shortness of breath is so severe that he is unable to speak clearly or quickly, but he manages to deny any recent surgery or history of recent bleeding. The vital signs include: blood pressure 111/69 mm Hg, pulse 142/min, and respiratory rate 33/min. On observation, he is using accessory muscles to breathe. On auscultation, his lungs are clear and his heart rate is rapid but regular. His right calf is swollen, warm, and tender. The arterial blood gas test result reveals a pH of 7.5, partial pressure of carbon dioxide (PCO2) 22 mm Hg, and a partial pressure of oxygen (PaO2) 47 mm Hg on 6 L of oxygen by nasal cannula. Which of the following is the most appropriate next step in the management of this patient?", "options": {"A": "Unfractionated heparin", "B": "Streptokinase", "C": "Low molecular-weight heparin", "D": "Embolectomy"}, "answer": "Streptokinase", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 37-year-old black male comes to the emergency department because his eyes have had a yellow discoloration and he has had dark urine for the past 3 days. He has also had fever, itching, and severe fatigue. He reports having symptoms of the stomach flu a week ago, which resolved with over-the-counter medication. He does not have diarrhea but says his stools are whitish in appearance. He has no personal history of serious illness. He does not smoke and drinks an average of 2 beers on weekends. He does not use illicit drugs. He has been sexually active with the same partner for 12 years and uses condoms consistently. He works as a flight attendant for an international airline. He appears ill. His temperature is 39.3°C (102.7°F), pulse is 64/min, and blood pressure is 132/82 mm Hg. Examination shows scleral icterus, excoriation marks over his extremities, and parched lips. The liver is tender on palpation; there is no splenomegaly. Cardiopulmonary examination is normal. Laboratory studies show: Hemoglobin 11.6 g/dL Leukocyte count 10,300/mm3 Platelet count 256,000/mm3 ESR 19 mm/hr Prothrombin time 13 seconds Serum Urea nitrogen 28 mg/dL Glucose 89 mg/dL Creatinine 0.7 mg/dL Bilirubin Total 8 mg/dL Direct 4 mg/dL ALP 80 U/L AST 312 U/L ALT 569 U/L An ultrasound of the abdomen shows no abnormalities. Serum studies are most likely to show which of the following findings?", "options": {"A": "Anti-mitochondrial antibodies", "B": "Perinuclear anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies", "C": "Anti-HAV IgM", "D": "Anti-HEV IgG"}, "answer": "Anti-HAV IgM", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician for back pain. The male states that his back pain is worse in the morning and improves with certain activities. He does not experience pain when cycling but notices the pain when standing or walking. 2 months prior to presentation he was lifting heavy boxes and furniture into his daughter's new home. He is requesting pain medication and a doctor's note to take off work for the week as his symptoms are disrupting his life. Which of the following is most likely to be seen in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Bamboo appearance of the spine on radiography", "B": "Muscular tenderness with perispinal palpation", "C": "Multiple doctors visits for other unrelated problems", "D": "Narrowing of the lumbar spinal canal on MRI"}, "answer": "Narrowing of the lumbar spinal canal on MRI", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male has been working in a sand blasting factory for over 25 years. He presents to his primary care physician with what he describes as increasing shortness of breath. PFTs are performed describing a restrictive lung process. Which of the following has most likely been the long-term mechanism of his disease development?", "options": {"A": "Eosinophilic reaction", "B": "Phagocytosis of silica", "C": "Tuberculosis", "D": "Defective mucociliary transport"}, "answer": "Phagocytosis of silica", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 63-year-old black male with a history of adult polycystic kidney disease and COPD presents to his optometrist after having difficulty watching a movie. He has no other complaints. He is accompanied by his daughter, who notes that his mother hasn't been able to look at them since the previous day. On exam, his right eye has full range of motion, but his left eye is fixed in a down and outward position. What is the most likely cause of his symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Vascular abnormality", "B": "Seizure", "C": "Demyelinating disease", "D": "Impaired dopaminergic neurons"}, "answer": "Vascular abnormality", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 73-year-old black male with a past medical history significant for high blood pressure, hypothyroidism, and diabetes presents to the outpatient clinic. He complains of joint pain, muscle pain, and fatigue that has been present for the last several weeks. On examination, you notice a butterfly-shaped rash across the bridge of his nose and cheeks. He has a blood pressure of 124/72 mm Hg and heart rate of 64/min. Of the following, which medication is most likely responsible for his presentation?", "options": {"A": "Verapamil", "B": "Clonidine", "C": "Hydralazine", "D": "Terazosin"}, "answer": "Hydralazine", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 65-year-old black male with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease is admitted to the hospital for the treatment of worsening shortness of breath and productive cough. Three days later, he complains of weakness in the lower limbs. His muscle strength is 4/5 at both hips but normal elsewhere. The drug that is most likely responsible for this patient's muscle weakness inhibits which of the following?", "options": {"A": "Adenosine receptor", "B": "5-lipoxygenase", "C": "Myosin light-chain kinase", "D": "Nuclear factor-κB"}, "answer": "Nuclear factor-κB", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 25-year-old black male presents to the emergency department after a motor vehicle collision. He is currently complaining of chest pain and shortness of breath and seems rather confused. His temperature is 97.7°F (36.5°C), blood pressure is 94/54 mmHg, pulse is 170/min, respirations are 12/min, and oxygen saturation is 90% on room air. A 14-gauge needle is placed in the 2nd intercostal space on the patient's left, and his blood pressure increases to 104/74 mmHg and his pulse decreases to 100/min. Which of the following is the best next intervention for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Chest radiograph", "B": "Pericardiocentesis", "C": "Thoracotomy", "D": "Tube thoracostomy"}, "answer": "Tube thoracostomy", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 68-year-old black male is brought to the emergency room because of pain in his right shoulder after falling down the stairs in his apartment. He has a history of postmenopausal osteoporosis. His current medications are alendronate, vitamin D, and calcium supplementation. Physical examination shows shortening of the right arm as well as tenderness and swelling over the right shoulder. The range of motion of the right arm is limited by pain. An x-ray of the right shoulder shows a fracture of the surgical neck of the humerus. Which of the following movements is most likely to be impaired in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Wrist extension", "B": "Elbow flexion", "C": "Arm abduction", "D": "Thumb adduction"}, "answer": "Arm abduction", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with recent onset confusion and photophobia. Upon questioning his partner, you discover the male has been sick over the past week with fevers and productive sputum. His vital signs are Temperature 102.6 Pulse 80 Respirations 18 Blood Pressure 110/70. The physical exam is significant for lethargy and nuchal rigidity. A lumbar puncture is performed and demonstrates cloudy fluid with an opening pressure of 35 cm H20, cell count of 1500 cells/uL (neutrophil predominant), protein level of 50 mg/dL and glucose of 30 mg/dL. Computed tomography scan demonstrates no space-occupying lesions. What is the most appropriate initial treatment for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Acyclovir", "B": "Ceftriaxone and dexamethasone", "C": "Vancomycin, ceftriaxone, ampicillin and dexamethasone", "D": "Vancomycin, ceftriaxone and ampicillin"}, "answer": "Vancomycin, ceftriaxone, ampicillin and dexamethasone", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male comes to the emergency department because of left arm pain after falling from a ladder. Physical examination shows tenderness along the proximal left humerus. An x-ray of the left arm and shoulder shows a nondisplaced proximal humerus fracture. Which of the following cytokines is most likely to be involved in normal bone healing in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Interleukin-4", "B": "Interferon-α", "C": "Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor", "D": "Macrophage colony-stimulating factor"}, "answer": "Macrophage colony-stimulating factor", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents with loss of consciousness at work. The patient's colleagues say that he had been complaining of a headache all day. His past medical history is significant for diabetes mellitus type 1. His blood pressure is 70/60 mm Hg, pulse is 105/min, temperature is 37.2°C (99.0°F), and his respiratory rate is 28/min and shallow. On physical examination, there is a black eschar formation on his nose and his breath has a fruity odor. Laboratory findings are significant for serum glucose of 750 mg/dL, potassium of 3.3 mmol/L, and blood pH of 7.1. Which of the following diabetic complications is most likely the cause of this patient's presenting symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Diabetic ketoacidosis", "B": "Hyperosmolar coma", "C": "Lactic acidosis", "D": "Hypoglycemic coma"}, "answer": "Diabetic ketoacidosis", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male presents with worsening weakness of the left hand and progressive difficulty in walking for the last 2 months. He says he was previously healthy and active, hiking every weekend, but because of his increasing weakness and incoordination while walking, he stopped his weekly hiking excursion. His past medical history is unremarkable. Current medications are a daily multivitamin and occasional acetaminophen for headaches. He has no significant family history. The male denies smoking, recreational drug use, or drinking. His vitals include: pulse 70/min, respirations 14/min, temperature 37.0°C (98.6°F), and blood pressure 130/80 mm Hg. Physical examination reveals fasciculations in the tongue and distal extremities. The left forearm shows significant atrophy, and mild lower limb muscle atrophy is also seen bilaterally. Hyporeflexia (1+) is present in the left arm, while hyperreflexia (3+) is seen in the legs bilaterally. Babinski's sign is positive bilaterally. The patient's speech is notably slow but no evidence of productive or expressive aphasia is present. The cranial nerves are intact. Which of the following pathologies most likely underlies this patient's condition?", "options": {"A": "Demyelination of neurons in various parts of the brain", "B": "Degeneration of the dorsal columns of the spinal cord", "C": "Infarction of the posterior limb of the internal capsule", "D": "Loss of the pyramidal tract neurons and anterior horn cells of the spinal cord"}, "answer": "Loss of the pyramidal tract neurons and anterior horn cells of the spinal cord", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 65-year-old black male with a history of coronary artery disease presents to your office complaining of ongoing chest pain with exertion. The male has had a recent cardiac work-up that showed no areas of acute ischemia. At the last visit, the male was prescribed sublingual nitroglycerin for symptom relief of stable angina. On further questioning, the male states that he has been swallowing the tablet whole instead of allowing it to dissolve because he \"does not like the taste\". What is the cause of the persistent symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Nitroglycerin tolerance", "B": "Unstable angina", "C": "First pass metabolism of nitroglycerin", "D": "Concomitant use of sildenafil"}, "answer": "First pass metabolism of nitroglycerin", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 65-year-old black male presents to the physician with a concern for several lumps on his jaw. He has a history of dental caries and admits to maintaining poor oral hygiene. On physical examination, he has 3 nontender and indurated masses at the angle of his jaw that are draining thick yellow pus. Microscopy of the drained pus reveals yellow granules filled with bacteria. Which of the following medical treatments is indicated for this patient's condition?", "options": {"A": "Amoxicillin-clavulanate", "B": "Dapsone and rifampin", "C": "Penicillin", "D": "Trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole"}, "answer": "Penicillin", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 30-year-old black male complains of heat intolerance, excessive sweating, and recent unintentional weight loss. He denies alcohol, tobacco, and other drug use and does not take any medications. Laboratory analysis reveals elevated serum T4 and decreased serum TSH. You elect to manage the patient's condition pharmacologically with methimazole. Methimazole interferes with the function of which of the following proteins?", "options": {"A": "Sex-hormone binding globulin", "B": "Thyroid peroxidase", "C": "5'-deiodinase", "D": "Sodium/iodide symporter"}, "answer": "Thyroid peroxidase", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 67-year-old black male presents to his physician's office with a progressive cough. It has been increasing in intensity over the past week. He has also been noticing an increase in the amount of sputum he usually produces, which is thick and yellow. He also complains of increased difficulty in breathing, more so than he previously experienced. He was diagnosed with chronic obstructive lung disease (COPD) about 3 years ago and has been on treatment for it since then. He doesn't report any fever, chills, or night sweats. He has observed a foul smell to his sputum. His blood pressure is 100/65 mm Hg, the respirations are 23/min and the pulse is about 110/min. Currently, his FEV1 is around 48% of the normal predicted value. He is currently receiving a yearly influenza shot and has taken the pneumococcal vaccination at the time of his diagnosis. In spite of this, he has had acute exacerbations of his symptoms 4 times over the last year. His last episode was 2 months ago, for which he was treated with a short course of antibiotics. He is also currently receiving treatment for diabetes. Which of the following pathogens should be considered before initiating treatment for the current episode?", "options": {"A": "S. pneumonia", "B": "H. influenzae", "C": "P. aeruginosa", "D": "Syncytial virus"}, "answer": "P. aeruginosa", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 66-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician with abdominal pain in the setting of progressively worsening constipation. He complains of epigastric pain that waxes and wanes, and expressed concern that he has not defecated for the past 5 days. Upon further questioning, he relates that he has been taking three of his partner's multivitamins each day for the past three weeks to \"combat a cold.\" Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical exam reveals an abdomen with nonspecific tenderness to deep palpation without rebound tenderness, hyperpercussion, or flank tenderness. What is the most likely cause of his symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Magnesium overdose", "B": "Iron overdose", "C": "Potassium overdose", "D": "Folic acid overdose"}, "answer": "Iron overdose", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 54-year-old black male comes to the physician for a follow-up appointment. Three weeks ago he underwent emergent cardiac catheterization because of a myocardial infarction and had to stay at the hospital longer than expected because of decreased kidney function. He says his symptoms have since improved greatly and he now produces even more urine than before the procedure. His serum creatinine concentration is 1.6 mg/dL and blood urea nitrogen concentration is 20 mg/dL.This male is at increased risk for which of the following complications?", "options": {"A": "Hypermagnesemia", "B": "Metabolic alkalosis", "C": "Hypernatremia", "D": "Hypokalemia"}, "answer": "Hypokalemia", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 31-year-old black male presents to the clinic as a follow-up visit after recently being diagnosed with medullary thyroid cancer. Last year, he was diagnosed with a pheochromocytoma that was successfully resected. His family history is positive for medullary thyroid cancer in his father and paternal grandmother with a mucosal neuroma in his brother. What additional finding is most likely to be present in this male on physical examination?", "options": {"A": "Ash leaf spot", "B": "Pituitary adenoma", "C": "Neurofibromas", "D": "Marfanoid habitus"}, "answer": "Marfanoid habitus", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 70-year-old black male comes to the physician because of fatigue and intermittent epigastric pain. The symptoms began about one year ago. He describes the pain as diffuse and 3 out of 10 in intensity. Recently, he has had unusually large black stools. He appears pale. His pulse is 72/min and his blood pressure is 110/70 mm Hg. Physical examination shows epigastric tenderness. A urea breath test is positive. Upper gastrointestinal endoscopy reveals an ulcerating mass in the gastric antrum. Biopsies of the mass show diffuse infiltrates of small lymphoid cells that are positive for CD20 antigen. A CT scan of the chest and abdomen shows normal regional lymph nodes. Which of the following is the most appropriate therapy with curative intent at this time?", "options": {"A": "Rituximab, cyclophosphamide, adriamycin, and vincristine", "B": "Imatinib", "C": "External beam radiation therapy", "D": "Amoxicillin, clarithromycin, and omeprazole"}, "answer": "Amoxicillin, clarithromycin, and omeprazole", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 45-year-old black male is brought by ambulance to your emergency room after complaining of shortness of breath along with profuse sweating at a company social function. His vitals were notable for elevated blood pressure with a normal exam and a stable electrocardiogram. He has been seeing a psychiatrist recently for his depression and was prescribed phenelzine after failing treatment with a first-line antidepressant therapy. What must he have been exposed to at the party that led to such a dramatic side effect?", "options": {"A": "Norepinephrine", "B": "Tyramine", "C": "Gluten", "D": "Dopamine"}, "answer": "Tyramine", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents for follow up 3 months after starting an antiretroviral regimen consisting of efavirenz, tenofovir, and emtricitabine. Labs drawn just prior to presentation reveal an undetectable viral load and a T-lymphocyte count of 317/mm^3. By comparison, his viral load was 6100/mL and his T-lymphocyte count was 146/mm^3 at the time of treatment initiation. He reports that he is tolerating the medications well and is not experiencing any major side effects. Which of the following treatment regimens should be recommended for this male given the fully suppressed viral load?", "options": {"A": "Continue current regimen of efavirenz, tenofovir, and emtricitabine", "B": "Continue efavirenz and emtricitabine but discontinue tenofovir", "C": "Continue efavirenz and tenofovir but discontinue emtricitabine", "D": "Continue tenofovir and emtricitabine but discontinue efavirenz"}, "answer": "Continue current regimen of efavirenz, tenofovir, and emtricitabine", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician with a 2-month history of fatigue. He says that he has been feeling tired, even after mild exertion, and decided to be evaluated because it has begun interfering with his job as a construction worker. He reports that he has been feeling numbness and tingling in his feet and has been tripping more frequently. His past medical history is significant for hypertension and type 2 diabetes well-controlled on metformin. His surgical history is significant for weight-loss surgery 2 years ago. Physical exam reveals bilateral vibration sensory deficits as well as conjunctival pallor. Selected lab results are presented as follows: Hemoglobin: 9.1 g/dL Hematocrit: 27% Platelet count: 265,000/mm^3 Mean corpuscular volume: 112 µm^3 Reticulocyte count: 0.19% Which of the following findings would most likely also be seen in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Elevated bilirubin levels", "B": "High methylmalonic acid and high homocysteine levels", "C": "High transferrin levels", "D": "Low haptoglobin levels"}, "answer": "High methylmalonic acid and high homocysteine levels", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 72-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician because he is coughing pink sputum and has difficulty breathing. He says that he was feeling pretty good until he traveled to his grandson's wedding last week. Since then he has had increasing difficulty sleeping and walking due to his shortness of breath. Physical exam reveals swollen ankles, basilar crackles bilaterally, and a murmur best heard in the left lateral decubitus position. He is already taking several medications for this condition; however, given the recent worsening of symptoms he has started on an additional medication. Which of the following is the most likely mechanism of action for the medication that was started in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Competitive inhibition of hormonal signaling", "B": "Decrease in adenylyl cyclase activity", "C": "Inhibition of Na-Cl symporter", "D": "Inhibition of Na-K-Cl cotransporter"}, "answer": "Inhibition of Na-K-Cl cotransporter", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 16-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department because of severe left flank pain and nausea for 3 hours. The pain is colicky and radiates towards his groin. He drinks multiple glasses of iced tea every day. He has had similar episodes of abdominal pain in the past. His maternal uncle has a similar history of abdominal pain. His temperature is 37.1°C (98.8°F), pulse is 103/min, and blood pressure is 108/72 mm Hg. Examination shows a soft and nontender abdomen. Left costovertebral angle tenderness is present. An x-ray of the abdomen shows no abnormalities. A urinary cyanide nitroprusside test is positive. Further evaluation of this male is most likely to show which of the following?", "options": {"A": "Rhomboid crystals on urinalysis", "B": "Urinary pH of 7.8", "C": "Serum anti-Saccharomyces cerevisiae antibodies", "D": "Hexagon-shaped crystals on urinalysis"}, "answer": "Hexagon-shaped crystals on urinalysis", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 65-year-old black male with hypertension came to the emergency department because of a sudden onset of a severe headache 2 hours ago. His temperature is 35°C (95°F) and blood pressure is 189/115 mm Hg. A CT scan of the head shows a subarachnoid hemorrhage and he is started on appropriate pharmacotherapy. Which of the following regions of the brain is most likely affected?", "options": {"A": "Ventral lateral thalamic nucleus", "B": "Pineal gland", "C": "Preoptic nucleus", "D": "Caudate nucleus"}, "answer": "Preoptic nucleus", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 37-year-old black male with a history of type II diabetes mellitus presents to the emergency department complaining of blood in his urine, left-sided flank pain, nausea, and fever. He also states that he has pain with urination. Vital signs include: temperature is 102 deg F (39.4 deg C), blood pressure is 114/82 mmHg, pulse is 96/min, respirations are 18, and oxygen saturation of 97% on room air. On physical examination, the male appears uncomfortable and has tenderness on the left flank and left costovertebral angle. Which of the following is the next best step in management?", "options": {"A": "Obtain an abdominal CT scan", "B": "Obtain a urine analysis and urine culture", "C": "Begin intravenous treatment with ceftazidime", "D": "No treatment is necessary"}, "answer": "Obtain a urine analysis and urine culture", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 73-year-old black male with a past medical history of diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia presents to the emergency department with swelling in his left neck. The onset was a few months ago. He has lost 6.8 kg (15.0 lb) over the same duration. He denies any fever, night sweats or itching. Physical examination reveals a painless swelling in front of his left ear. There is painless lymphadenopathy below the ear. Biopsy of the lymph nodes reveals mucoepidermoid carcinoma of the parotid gland. Surgery is planned and the tumor is removed while trying to preserve a nerve that could be involved. What physical finding would suggest involvement of the nerve in its course through the parotid gland?", "options": {"A": "Loss of taste on the left anterior 2/3 of the tongue", "B": "Hypersensitivity to sound in the left ear", "C": "Inability to smile on the left side", "D": "Numbness of the left cheek"}, "answer": "Inability to smile on the left side", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 52-year-old black male presents to the clinic complaining of sudden onset of flank tenderness that was fluctuating and radiating into his groin. Laboratory analysis reveals a serum calcium of 12.4 (normal 8.4-10.2) and a serum phosphorous of 2.5 (normal 2.7-4.5) and a chloride:phosphorous ratio >33. You suspect primary hyperparathyroidism. Which of the following mechanisms is responsible for the patient's current condition?", "options": {"A": "PTH binding to receptors on osteoclasts", "B": "Parafollicular, or C-cell, synthesis of calcitonin", "C": "Increased RANK-L production", "D": "Decreased M-CSF production"}, "answer": "Increased RANK-L production", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male who was involved in a motor vehicle collision is brought into the emergency room with a fractured skull. The paramedics report that the male was conscious and lucid on the way to the hospital but now is unresponsive. His vitals are a blood pressure of 122/78 mm Hg, temperature of 37.0°C (98.6°F), pulse rate of 88/min, and respiratory rate of 14/min. A noncontrast CT scan of the head shows an epidural hematoma. Which of the following structures is involved in the development of an epidural hematoma?", "options": {"A": "Middle meningeal artery", "B": "Bridging cortical veins", "C": "Arteriovenous malformation", "D": "Lenticulostriate vessels"}, "answer": "Middle meningeal artery", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 72-year-old black male is brought in by ambulance after being found down in his home. His daughter discovered them after returning from work and does not know how long he has been down. Physical exam reveals right sided paralysis with a positive babinski sign. He is also found to produce strained stuttering speech with no perceivable meaning. He is unable to follow any instructions and cannot repeat speech. An MRI is obtained showing a left MCA infarct. Damage to which of the following structures is most likely to be responsible for his language deficits?", "options": {"A": "Arcuate fasciculus", "B": "Inferior frontal gyrus", "C": "Inferior frontal gyrus + superior temporal gyrus", "D": "Arcuate fasciculus + Inferior frontal gyrus + superior temporal gyrus"}, "answer": "Arcuate fasciculus + Inferior frontal gyrus + superior temporal gyrus", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with complaints of acute-onset fatigue, blurred vision, and rash earlier today. His partner rushed them to the emergency department when they noted that he was exhibiting changes in his mental status and had trouble speaking. His vital signs are as follows: T 38.4, HR 87, BP 110/85, RR 14, and SpO2 96%. Physical examination reveals petechiae, pallor, and left upper extremity weakness. Work-up reveals Hgb 8.5 g/dL, platelets 22,000 cells/uL, normal PT/INR and PTT, absent fibrin split products, elevated fibrinogen, a negative Coombs test, 3.7 mg/dL creatinine, 3.8 mg/dL indirect bilirubin, and LDH 1000 IU/L. Which of the following would be expected on a peripheral blood smear from this patient?", "options": {"A": "Spherocytes", "B": "Atypical lymphocytes", "C": "Schistocytes", "D": "Rouleaux formation"}, "answer": "Schistocytes", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents with diarrhea, fatigue and weight loss. He says he has been having occasional loose stools and abdominal pain for the past month, but he did not seek any medical attention because of work deadlines. He says the diarrhea is associated with cramping lower abdominal pain and an urgency to defecate. His stool is loose, occasionally blood-tinged, and contains mucus. He also says he feels fatigued and has lost 11 kg (24 lb) over the last 2 months. The male denies any fever, sick contacts, or a history of recent travel. No significant past medical history. Family history is significant for colon cancer in his father, who died at the age of 50. On physical examination, the male has generalized pallor. Abdominal exam reveals mild tenderness to palpation in the left lower quadrant. Laboratory investigations reveal microcytic anemia with an elevated ESR. A colonoscopy with biopsy is performed, which shows inflammation of the sigmoid colon and rectum. Biopsy shows a predominantly lymphoid infiltration of the mucosa and submucosa with multiple crypt abscesses. No evidence of granulomatous disease. What is the mechanism of action of the drug which typically induces remission of this patient's most likely condition?", "options": {"A": "Inhibition of prostaglandins and inflammatory cytokines", "B": "Antibody against tumor necrosis factor", "C": "Inhibition of cellular metabolism", "D": "Suppression of polymorphonuclear cell migration"}, "answer": "Inhibition of prostaglandins and inflammatory cytokines", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 45-year-old black male presents to the emergency room with fever and headache. He recently had a middle ear infection. On physical examination, when the head is passively flexed towards the chest, then flexion of the knee is observed. In addition, he reports that his headache increases after rotating his head horizontally. Lumbar puncture and CSF analysis were done. Which of the following laboratory findings would best represent your suspected diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Glucose: ↑, Proteins: ↑, Cells: 10% lymphocytes, Lactic Acid (mmol/l): 3.0", "B": "Glucose: ↓, Proteins: normal, Cells: 10% lymphocytes, Lactic Acid (mmol/l): 2.8", "C": "Glucose: ↑, Proteins: ↓, Cells: 90% neutrophils , Lactic Acid (mmol/l): 4.3", "D": "Glucose: ↓, Proteins: ↑, Cells: 90% neutrophils, Lactic Acid (mmol/l): 4.5"}, "answer": "Glucose: ↓, Proteins: ↑, Cells: 90% neutrophils, Lactic Acid (mmol/l): 4.5", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with a chief concern of abdominal pain and diarrhea. The male states that for the past 4 days he has experienced abdominal pain, diarrhea, weakness and a subjective fever. He also endorses a weight loss of 11 pounds during this time. The male has a past medical history of celiac disease, constipation, and depression. His current medications include fish oil, a multivitamin, sodium docusate, and fluoxetine. His temperature is 98.5°F (36.9°C), blood pressure is 110/75 mmHg, pulse is 90/min, respirations are 13/min, and oxygen saturation is 98% on room air. Physical exam is notable for a young male in mild distress. Cardiac and pulmonary exams are within normal limits. Abdominal exam is notable for generalized tenderness and increased bowel sounds. Oral exam is notable for multiple shallow painful ulcers. Laboratory values are ordered as seen below: Hemoglobin: 12 g/dL Hematocrit: 36% Leukocyte count: 8,000 cells/mm^3 with normal differential Platelet count: 227,500/mm^3 Serum: Na+: 141 mEq/L Cl-: 101 mEq/L K+: 4.5 mEq/L HCO3-: 24 mEq/L BUN: 17 mg/dL Glucose: 82 mg/dL Creatinine: 1.0 mg/dL Ca2+: 10.1 mg/dL AST: 12 U/L ALT: 11 U/L A stool guaiac test is performed which returns positive. The male is started on IV fluids and morphine. Which of the following best describes the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "ANCA positivity", "B": "ASCA positivity", "C": "Dilated vascular structure in the anal canal", "D": "Mucosal disruption"}, "answer": "ASCA positivity", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 68-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician with complaints of fatigue, difficulty breathing upon exertion, and crampy lower abdominal pain. He also notices that his stools are dark. He has had essential hypertension for 20 years for which he takes bisoprolol. His family history is positive for type 2 diabetes mellitus. On physical examination, he looks pale. Complete blood count shows the following: Hemoglobin 10 g/dL Mean corpuscular volume (MCV) 70 fL Mean corpuscular hemoglobin (MCH) 25 pg/cell Mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (MCHC) 27 g/dL Red cell distribution width 16% Platelet count 350,000/mm3 Serum ferritin is 9 ng/mL. The male is referred to a gastroenterologist and conventional colonoscopy reveals a polypoid mass in the ascending colon. Biopsy shows poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma. A preoperative staging is performed and a laparoscopic cancer resection with postoperative chemotherapy are planned. Which of the following tests can be used for postoperative follow up of this patient?", "options": {"A": "Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA)", "B": "Pelvic magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)", "C": "Transrectal endoscopic ultrasound (TRUS)", "D": "Cancer antigen 125 (CA 125)"}, "answer": "Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA)", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 36-year-old black male presents with a persistent cough productive of blood-streaked sputum, night sweats, and weight loss. No significant past medical history. He denies any history of smoking, alcohol consumption, or recreational drug use. He works as a nurse at a local hospital and lives in an apartment with his extended family. His vital signs are a blood pressure of 100/80 mm Hg, heart rate of 94/min, respiratory rate of 17/min, and temperature of 35.9℃ (96.6℉). Physical examination reveals dullness to percussion and diminished breath sounds over the upper lobe of the left lung. During the discussion regarding the required workup, the male tells the physician about recent contact with a male with tuberculosis. He asks the physician not to report his case because he is concerned he will lose his job. Which of the following statements is correct?", "options": {"A": "If this patient is diagnosed with active pulmonary tuberculosis, it should be reported even without the patient's consent, and the patient should receive isolation and treatment.", "B": "The patient has a right to privacy, so, without their consent, the physician can not report their case even if they are diagnosed with active pulmonary tuberculosis.", "C": "If this patient turns out to have active pulmonary tuberculosis, their case can stay unreported only if they agree to stay home from work and remain isolated at home for their entire treatment period.", "D": "Only active pulmonary tuberculosis is a reportable disease."}, "answer": "If this patient is diagnosed with active pulmonary tuberculosis, it should be reported even without the patient's consent, and the patient should receive isolation and treatment.", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 30-year-old black male is brought to the doctor's office by his partner. They complain that over the past week there have been 3 episodes where he has fallen asleep while speaking with [her]. They mentioned that these events began a few months ago and have been increasing in frequency. They also say that his snoring has gotten to the point where they have a hard time sleeping next to them. When asked, the male says that he frequently falls asleep while reading or watching television in the afternoons and feels refreshed after a short nap. The male is worried because he sometimes hears people who aren't in the room as he falls asleep. He is worried he might be \"going crazy.\" He has noticed that when his friends tell them a joke or he laughs at something on the TV, he drops whatever he is holding and feels like his legs become weak. These episodes self-resolve in a few seconds. Examination shows a morbidly obese male in no acute distress. Which of the following is the best treatment for the most likely cause for this patient's illness?", "options": {"A": "Modafinil", "B": "Taking longer naps", "C": "Continuous positive airway pressure", "D": "Changing bedtime to earlier in the evening"}, "answer": "Modafinil", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 26-year-old black male is admitted to the hospital because of a 3-day history of tingling and weakness in the lower extremities. Neurologic examination shows areflexia of the ankle and knee joints bilaterally. Motor strength is 1/5 in both lower legs. Over the next 3 weeks, the patient's condition progresses to involve both upper extremities, and he requires ventilatory support. Six weeks after admission, deep tendon reflexes are 1+ in the ankles, and he is able to wiggle his toes. Which of the following is most likely responsible for the improvement in this patient's neurological status?", "options": {"A": "Synthesis of monoamine neurotransmitters", "B": "Remyelination of peripheral nerves", "C": "Replication of oligodendrocyte precursor cells", "D": "Lymphocytic infiltration in the endoneurium\n"}, "answer": "Remyelination of peripheral nerves", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 45-year-old black male comes to the physician because of a 4-month history of increased frequency of urination. He wakes up several times a night to urinate and feels fatigued during the day. He also complains of increased thirst; he drinks multiple liters of water and soda daily and still feels thirsty. Vital signs are within normal limits. Physical examination shows patches of velvety hyperpigmentation in the axilla and on the posterior neck. Laboratory evaluation in this male is most likely to show which of the following?", "options": {"A": "Elevated serum thyroxine concentration", "B": "Elevated glycated hemoglobin concentration", "C": "Positive urinary leukocyte esterase", "D": "Low urine osmolality"}, "answer": "Elevated glycated hemoglobin concentration", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 17-year-old black male is brought in by paramedics to the emergency department. He was found down at a family picnic. The male parents state that he tried many new foods at the picnic. Additionally, because it is springtime, many insects were out while he was playing football. His temperature is 99.5°F (37.5°C), blood pressure is 127/68 mmHg, pulse is 120/min, respirations are 33/min, and oxygen saturation is 84% on room air. Physical exam is notable for tachycardia and very minimal breath sounds bilaterally. No jugular venous distention is noted and an abdominal exam is within normal limits. Which of the following best describes an effect of the next best step in management?", "options": {"A": "Decreased serum potassium", "B": "Equilibration of environmental and chest cavity pressure", "C": "Hypoglycemia", "D": "Increased systemic vascular resistance"}, "answer": "Decreased serum potassium", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 37-year-old black male comes to the physician because of a 3-month history of worsening painful swallowing, hoarseness, and bilateral otalgia. He has had a 10-kg (22-lb) weight loss during this period. He does not smoke or drink alcohol. Laryngoscopic examination shows an abnormal mass located on the right true vocal cord. Immunohistochemistry of the mass shows expression of HPV-16 DNA. This neoplasm most likely derived from which of the following types of epithelial tissue?", "options": {"A": "Stratified squamous epithelium with submucosal glands", "B": "Simple columnar epithelium with cilia", "C": "Pseudostratified columnar epithelium with cilia", "D": "Pseudostratified columnar epithelium with cartilage"}, "answer": "Stratified squamous epithelium with submucosal glands", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 59-year-old black male is brought to the emergency room by his partner. Thirty minutes ago, he was carrying heavy moving boxes from his house to a truck when he felt short of breath and suddenly lost consciousness. His partner states that he fell to the ground and was unresponsive for 15 seconds before he regained consciousness. He was not confused after this episode. He does not have chest pain. On questioning, he recalls experiencing episodic shortness of breath and chest tightness while playing tennis over the past year. These symptoms are resolved with rest. He has no personal history of serious illness and takes no medication. Vital signs are within normal limits. His temperature is 36.7°C (98°F), heart rate is 95/min and pulse is delayed but regular, respirations are 20/min, and blood pressure is 104/80 mm Hg. Which of the following is most likely to confirm the diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "CT angiography", "B": "Echocardiogram", "C": "Cardiac enzymes", "D": "Electroencephalogram\n"}, "answer": "Echocardiogram", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 19-year-old black male college student comes to the physician for a sudden loss of visual acuity of his right eye. He noticed that he was unable to read the time on the alarm clock when he woke up in the morning. When he closes his right eye, he is able to see sharply. When he closes his left eye, he has blurry double vision. He does not recall trauma to his eye but has been working long nights on his honors thesis. He has a history of occasional shoulder luxation. He is 180 cm (5 ft 11 in) tall, and weighs 62 kg (136 lbs); his BMI is 19.1 kg/m2. His vital signs are within normal limits. On physical examination, slender and long fingers are noted. He has several flat, demarcated brownish nevi on his left cheek. Ocular examination shows upward temporal subluxation of his right lens. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Joint hypermobility syndrome", "B": "Sturge-Weber syndrome", "C": "Ehlers-Danlos syndrome", "D": "Marfan syndrome"}, "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 23-year-old black male develops a seizure on the medical floor. He was admitted 2 days ago with high-grade fever and severe headache. At the time of admission, he had photophobia, neck rigidity, and the following vital signs: temperature 39.5°C (103.1°F), blood pressure 130/70 mm Hg, and heart rate 120/min. A cerebral spinal fluid analysis was ordered, and he was started on intravenous antibiotics. The patient's seizure terminates without any medication or intervention. An MRI is performed which reveals dilation of all the ventricles of the brain. Which of the following is the most likely cause of his abnormal radiologic findings?", "options": {"A": "Blood clot in the foramen of 3rd ventricle", "B": "Aqueductal stenosis", "C": "Arachnoid granulation adhesions", "D": "Mega cisterna magna"}, "answer": "Arachnoid granulation adhesions", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 60-year-old black male calls his hospital and asks to speak to his physician about laboratory test reports ordered because of a 3-month history of abdominal fullness and generalized fatigue. The referral note shows that he was constipated for the previous week. His abdominal examination had shown distention, and a 7-cm, hard, irregular, nontender mass was palpable on rectal examination. His colonoscopy report reveals a low anterior circumferential rectal lesion. An MRI of the pelvis shows a rectal mass with involvement of the prostate and seminal vesicles. A brief review of the results shows that an endoscopic biopsy confirms the clinical diagnosis of advanced rectal adenocarcinoma. His serum carcinoembryonic antigen concentration is 21.0 ng/mL (N < 2.5). The physician is tasked with delivering the diagnosis to the patient. Which of the following is the most appropriate statement by the physician at this time?", "options": {"A": "Your lab reports show that you have a locally advanced rectal adenocarcinoma", "B": "Would you like to know all the details of your diagnosis, or would you prefer I just explain to you what our options are?", "C": "I would like to meet later today at 4:00 PM so that we have enough time to discuss the lab results. If you'd like a friend or family member to accompany you, feel free to bring them along.", "D": "You must be be curious as to why all these tests were ordered, and you may even be anxious about the results."}, "answer": "I would like to meet later today at 4:00 PM so that we have enough time to discuss the lab results. If you'd like a friend or family member to accompany you, feel free to bring them along.", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 39-year-old black male is brought to the emergency room by his partner for severe abdominal pain for the past 5 hours. He was watching TV after dinner when he felt a sudden, sharp, 10/10 pain at the epigastric region that did not go away. Ibuprofen also did not help. He reports recurrent abdominal pain that would self-resolve in the past but states that \"this one is way worse.\" His past medical history is significant for diabetes and an appendectomy 2 years ago. The male endorses nausea and 1 episode of emesis, but denies fevers, chills, chest pain, shortness of breath, diarrhea, constipation, urinary symptoms, paresthesia, or weakness. He used to smoke marijuana in college and drinks about 2 beers a week. A physical examination demonstrates an overweight male in acute distress with diffuse abdominal tenderness. His vitals are within normal limits. Laboratory values are shown below: Hemoglobin: 12 g/dL Hematocrit: 34% Leukocyte count: 4,900/mm^3 with normal differential Platelet count: 160,000/mm^3 Serum: Na+: 138 mEq/L Cl-: 98 mEq/L K+: 4.8 mEq/L HCO3-: 25 mEq/L Glucose: 123 mg/dL Ca2+: 6.9 mg/dL AST: 387 U/L ALT: 297 U/L ALP: 168 U/L Lipase: 650 U/L (Normal 0 – 160 U/L) What is the best next step in the workup of this patient?", "options": {"A": "Abdominal computed tomography without IV contrast", "B": "Abdominal magnetic resonance imaging", "C": "Abdominal ultrasound", "D": "Upright chest and abdominal radiograph"}, "answer": "Abdominal ultrasound", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 37-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician with a chief complaint of diarrhea. The male states that his symptoms have worsened recently. He works as a farmer and is dressed in tattered and old denim. He lives alone, and this is the first time he has come to town in years. The patient's diet is mostly dairy products and some meat products. He denies any systemic symptoms and states that diarrhea tends to occur right after a meal. He also claims that at times he struggles to fall asleep, and sometimes he feels he lacks energy. The male is instructed to avoid consuming dairy products for a week and to return with a report of his symptoms. As you set up the return appointment with this male you notice that he is rather emotionless. He also states that he lacks anybody that he can list as an emergency contact so he leaves that section of his medical forms blank. What is the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Avoidant personality disorder", "B": "Major depressive disorder", "C": "Schizoid personality disorder", "D": "Schizotypal personality disorder"}, "answer": "Schizoid personality disorder", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician's office with fatigue, headaches, and concentration difficulties. His symptoms began approximately 7 months prior to presentation. Throughout this time, he reports problems with initiating and remaining asleep, has noticed periods of muscle soreness, and has feelings of restlessness. He states that he is very concerned about whether he will be able to pay his monthly expenses and if his parents are satisfied with his career choices. He is also worried about how his colleagues and supervisor think of his performance at work. He denies any significant past medical history besides occasional palpitations. He takes a daily multivitamin. Family history is significant for panic disorder in his mother. He currently lives alone and at times socializes with friends. He occasionally drinks alcohol during social gatherings, does not smoke, and denies any illicit drug use. His temperature is 99°F (37.2 °C), blood pressure is 110/75, pulse is 101/min, and respirations are 18/min. Physical examination is unremarkable. Which of the following is the most appropriate pharmacologic treatment for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Buspirone", "B": "Mirtazapine", "C": "Olanzapine", "D": "Trazodone"}, "answer": "Buspirone", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 65-year-old black male presents to the Emergency Department complaining of substernal chest pain. An acute coronary event is suspected and a coronary catheterization procedure reveals an atherosclerotic plaque in the patient's left anterior descending artery. In the formation of an atherosclerotic plaque, which of the following pairings is correct?", "options": {"A": "Fibroblasts -- foam cells", "B": "Smooth muscle cells (SMC) -- extracellular matrix (ECM) deposition", "C": "Endothelial cells -- downregulation of VCAM-1", "D": "LDL chemical reduction -- endothelial dysfunction"}, "answer": "Smooth muscle cells (SMC) -- extracellular matrix (ECM) deposition", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 26-year-old black male comes to the physician because of high-grade fever, fatigue, nausea, and headache for 4 days. The headache is constant and feels like a tight band around his head. He also reports that his eyes hurt while looking at bright lights. He has been taking acetaminophen and using cold towels to help relieve his symptoms. He works as an assistant for a nature camp organization but has been unable to go to work for 3 days. His immunization records are unavailable. His temperature is 38.5°C (101.3°F), pulse is 92/min, and blood pressure is 108/74 mm Hg. He is oriented to time, place, and person. There is no rash or lymphadenopathy. Flexion of the neck results in flexion of the knee and hip. A lumbar puncture is done; cerebrospinal fluid analysis shows an opening pressure of 80 mm H2O, leukocyte count of 93/mm3 (78% lymphocytes), a glucose concentration of 64 mg/dL, and a protein concentration of 50 mg/dL. Which of the following is the most likely causal organism?", "options": {"A": "Borrelia burgdorferi", "B": "Mycobacterium tuberculosis", "C": "Herpes simplex virus 1", "D": "Coxsackievirus"}, "answer": "Coxsackievirus", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 42-year-old black male is being treated by his male family medicine physician for chronic depression. Recently, he has been scheduling more frequent office visits. He does not report any symptoms or problems with his SSRI medication during these visits. Upon further questioning, the male confesses that he is attracted to them and says \"You are the only one in the world who understands me\". The physician also manages his hypertension. Which of the following is the most appropriate next step in management?", "options": {"A": "Re-evaluate this patient for borderline personality disorder", "B": "Ask closed-ended questions and use a chaperone for future visits", "C": "Immediately tell this patient that you can not continue to treat them and avoid any further communication", "D": "Increase the dosage of this patient's SSRI"}, "answer": "Ask closed-ended questions and use a chaperone for future visits", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 52-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician for his annual check-up. He says that he has no health concerns; however, his partner is concerned that he has become increasingly forgetful. For example, he has become forgetful during his daily activities and recently has been getting lost during errands like shopping. He says that these symptoms have been occurring for about a year. He says that he became alarmed when he started forgetting the names of their children. Finally, over the last month he has become more irritable, which has led to several confrontations at work. Based on the age of onset for his disease, the male is referred for genetic testing. Which of the following chromosomes contain genes that may be mutated in this patient's disease?", "options": {"A": "1", "B": "4", "C": "18", "D": "20"}, "answer": "1", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 68-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician for pain in his feet. The male states that it is very painful for them to walk around, and he has significant pain in his right and left toes. The male has a past medical history of obesity, type II diabetes mellitus, anxiety, depression, COPD, and a 30 pack-year smoking history. The patient's current medications include lisinopril, hydrochlorothiazide, insulin, metformin, fluoxetine, clonazepam, albuterol, home oxygen, varenicline, and fish oil and he is compliant with all medications. On a physical exam, the patient's toes appear pale and dirty. When inspecting his toes, shallow wounds with a pale base devoid of granulation tissue can be appreciated. The male has decreased pinprick sensation in his lower extremities bilaterally. Pulmonary exam is notable for a prolonged expiratory phase. Which of the following findings is most likely to be found in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Bipedal edema", "B": "Increased reflexes of the lower extremities", "C": "Loss of vibration sensation in the lower extremities", "D": "Calf pain after walking moderate distance"}, "answer": "Calf pain after walking moderate distance", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 52-year-old black male with limited, unresectable small cell lung cancer comes to the emergency department because of fever for the past 2 days. He has been on numerous chemotherapy regimens. His last round of treatment was with cisplatin and etoposide and ended 10 days ago. He feels fatigued but has not had nausea or vomiting. His temperature is 38.5°C (101.3°F), blood pressure is 100/60 mm Hg, and pulse is 115/min. The lungs are clear to auscultation. Examination shows a soft, nontender abdomen. Laboratory studies show: Hemoglobin 10.2 g/dL Leukocyte count 4,000/mm3 Total neutrophils 8% Eosinophils 2% Lymphocytes 80% Monocytes 10% Urinalysis shows no abnormalities. Blood culture samples are obtained. Which of the following is the most appropriate next step in management?", "options": {"A": "Cefepime", "B": "Piperacillin", "C": "Clindamycin", "D": "High-resolution chest CT"}, "answer": "Cefepime", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 25-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department 30 minutes after he was involved in a motorcycle collision. Physical examination shows a deep laceration on the volar surface of the distal left forearm. Neurological examination shows loss of abduction and opposition of the left thumb. The radial and ulnar pulses are palpable. Based on these findings, which of the following nerves is most likely injured in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Posterior interosseous nerve", "B": "Axillary nerve", "C": "Median nerve", "D": "Ulnar nerve"}, "answer": "Median nerve", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 66-year-old black male presents to clinic for a blood glucose level of 169 mg/dL taken at a local pharmacy. He is a farmer in rural Alabama and has not seen a doctor for decades. He wants to be in excellent shape prior to his trip to visit his daughter at college. His past medical history and family history are unknown, and he does not take any medications. His diet consists of pork products and he does not smoke. His temperature is 99.5°F (37.5°C), pulse is 100/min, blood pressure is 169/90 mmHg, respirations are 18/min, and oxygen saturation is 97% on room air. The male is started on metformin, lisinopril, and a guided exercise program. Lab results are below: Serum: Na+: 145 mEq/L Cl-: 100 mEq/L K+: 4.9 mEq/L HCO3-: 24 mEq/L BUN: 18 mg/dL Glucose: 211 mg/dL Creatinine: 1.0 mg/dL Ca2+: 10.0 mg/dL He returns from his trip, complaining of cough. He denies any other symptoms. His temperature is 99.5°F (37.5°C), pulse is 101/min, blood pressure is 160/85 mmHg, respirations are 18/min, and oxygen saturation is 98% on room air. Repeat lab results are below: Serum: Na+: 145 mEq/L Cl-: 100 mEq/L K+: 5.3 mEq/L HCO3-: 24 mEq/L BUN: 22 mg/dL Glucose: 169 mg/dL Creatinine: 1.2 mg/dL Ca2+: 10.1 mg/dL What is the next best step in management?", "options": {"A": "Switch blood pressure medication to losartan", "B": "Switch blood pressure medication to hydrochlorothiazide", "C": "Azithromycin", "D": "Loratadine"}, "answer": "Switch blood pressure medication to losartan", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 36-year-old black male presents with right upper quadrant pain, fatigue, and pruritus. His past medical history is significant for ulcerative colitis diagnosed 5 years ago, which is well-managed medically. He is vaccinated against hepatitis A and B and denies any recent travel abroad. On physical examination, mild jaundice of the skin is present. An abdominal examination reveals significant hepatosplenomegaly. A percutaneous liver biopsy is performed. Which of the following histopathologic findings would most likely be seen on the liver biopsy of this patient?", "options": {"A": "Small drops of fat throughout the liver parenchyma", "B": "Normal histologic findings", "C": "Mononuclear cell infiltrate and apoptotic hepatocytes", "D": "Onion skin fibrosis (concentric periductal fibrosis)"}, "answer": "Onion skin fibrosis (concentric periductal fibrosis)", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 25-year-old black male is brought by his roommate to the emergency department with chest pain, which began 90 minutes ago. His roommate says that he has not slept within the past 24 hours and has been taking pills to help them study longer for his upcoming national dental board exam. On examination, he is diaphoretic, extremely agitated, and attempts to remove his IV lines and ECG leads. His temperature is 38.9°C (102.2°F), pulse is 115/min, and blood pressure is 160/102 mmHg. His pupil size is 7 mm bilaterally. The lungs are clear to auscultation. The most appropriate next step in management is administration of which of the following?", "options": {"A": "Lorazepam", "B": "Dantrolene", "C": "Ketamine", "D": "Haloperidol\n"}, "answer": "Lorazepam", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 6-year-old black male is rushed to the emergency department after being involved in a motor vehicle accident. He has abrasions on his left knee and left elbow. His wounds are cleaned and a pressure bandage is applied. Typically, neutrophils and macrophages are attracted toward the site of injury by various chemical mediators. Which of the following cells is responsible for the initial cascade by the release of TGF-β and PDGF?", "options": {"A": "Mast cells", "B": "Fibroblasts", "C": "Platelets", "D": "Basophils"}, "answer": "Platelets", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 38-year-old imprisoned black male is brought to the physician after going on a hunger strike for 36 hours. During this time, he has only had two cups of water. Physical examination shows dry mucous membranes. His serum glucose concentration is 70 mg/dL. Which of the following enzymes contributes most to maintaining a normal serum glucose level in this patient?", "options": {"A": "Phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase", "B": "Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA lyase", "C": "Glycogen phosphorylase", "D": "Phosphofructokinase-1"}, "answer": "Phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 50-year-old black male comes to the physician because of an 8-month history of intermittent watery diarrhea and abdominal pain. He has had a 12-kg (26-lb) weight loss during this period. He has also had episodic pain of the ankle, wrist, and knee joints during the past 5 years. An endoscopy with small bowel biopsy is performed. Histopathologic examination of a tissue specimen shows foamy macrophages in the lamina propria with periodic acid-Schiff (PAS)-positive inclusions. Further evaluation is most likely to show which of the following?", "options": {"A": "Anti-tissue transglutaminase antibodies", "B": "Anti-cyclic citrullinated peptide antibody", "C": "Intracellular, gram-positive bacilli", "D": "Low serum TSH and high free T4 concentrations"}, "answer": "Intracellular, gram-positive bacilli", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 55-year-old homeless black male presents to the emergency department acutely confused. The male was found wandering the streets with an abnormal gait. The male has a past medical history of alcohol and IV drug abuse. His temperature is 98.5°F (36.9°C), blood pressure is 103/61 mmHg, pulse is 120/min, respirations are 16/min, and oxygen saturation is 97% on room air. Physical exam is notable for a poorly kempt male with ataxic gait. Ophthalmoplegia is noted on cranial nerve testing, and he has decreased vibration sensation in the bilateral lower extremity. Dermatologic exam reveals perifollicular hemorrhages, bleeding gums, and many bruises along the patient's upper and lower extremities. An initial ECG is notable for sinus tachycardia and the male is given 2L of Ringer lactate. Laboratory values are ordered as seen below. Hemoglobin: 8.0 g/dL Hematocrit: 30% Leukocyte count: 3,500/mm^3 with normal differential Platelet count: 192,000/mm^3 MCV: 119 fL Serum: Na+: 139 mEq/L Cl-: 100 mEq/L K+: 4.3 mEq/L HCO3-: 25 mEq/L BUN: 20 mg/dL Glucose: 47 mg/dL Creatinine: 1 mg/dL Ca2+: 9.2 mg/dL Mg2+: 1.2 mEq/L AST: 82 U/L ALT: 70 U/L Which of the following is the best next treatment for this patient?", "options": {"A": "Folate", "B": "Magnesium", "C": "Thiamine", "D": "Vitamin C"}, "answer": "Thiamine", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 29-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department after being found unresponsive at home. The patient's roommate says that the male had previously been feeling well. The male and his roommate had a celebration the night before, where they drank homemade liquor. His temperature is 37°C (98.6°F), pulse is 126/min, respirations are 30/min and shallow, and blood pressure is 84/44 mm Hg. Pulse oximetry on room air shows an oxygen saturation of 96%. He is unresponsive to painful stimuli. The pupils are 3 mm, equal, round, and reactive to light. The lungs are clear to auscultation. Cardiac examination shows a grade 2/6 systolic murmur along the left parasternal border. Laboratory studies show: Serum Na+ 146 mmol/L K+ 7.7 mmol/L Cl- 111 mmol/L Urea nitrogen 5.8 mmol/L Glucose 83 mg/dL Lactate 11.2 mmol/L Serum osmolality 379 mosm/kg Arterial blood gas analysis shows: pH 6.69 pCO2 53 mm Hg pO2 84 mm Hg HCO3- 4.3 mmol/L The male is intubated and fluid resuscitation is begun. Which of the following is the most appropriate pharmacotherapy?", "options": {"A": "N-acetylcysteine", "B": "Fomepizole", "C": "Naloxone", "D": "Flumazenil"}, "answer": "Fomepizole", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 24-year-old black male is brought to the ED from a nearby nightclub by the local police due to aggressive and violent behavior over the past hour. A friend accompanying the male reports that the male smoked marijuana that \"seemed different\" approximately one hour ago. The male has never had this kind of reaction to marijuana use in the past. On examination, the male is combative with slurred speech and active visual hallucinations; eye examination shows prominent vertical nystagmus. This patient's presentation can be best explained by intoxication with a substance that acts at which of the following receptors?", "options": {"A": "Serotonin", "B": "Cannabinoid", "C": "NMDA", "D": "Norepinephrine"}, "answer": "NMDA", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 57-year-old black male comes to the emergency department 1 hour after experiencing a distressing 10-minute episode of stuttering during a business meeting. He has hypertension. He has smoked 2 packs of cigarettes daily for 30 years. Current medications include fosinopril and hydrochlorothiazide. His temperature is 37°C (98.6°F), pulse is 90/min, respirations are 16/min, and blood pressure is 134/88 mm Hg. He is oriented to person, place, and time. His speech is clear. When he is asked to hold both arms fully extended at shoulder level with palms upwards and eyes closed, his right palm turns inwards and downwards. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient's physical findings?", "options": {"A": "Cerebellar lesion", "B": "Inferior frontal gyrus lesion", "C": "Upper motor neuron lesion", "D": "Thalamus lesion"}, "answer": "Upper motor neuron lesion", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 36-year-old black male presents to his primary care physician for his yearly physical exam. He says that he has been experiencing some mild shortness of breath, but otherwise has no medical complaints. His past medical history is significant for allergies and asthma as a child, but he is not currently taking any medications or supplements. He does not smoke and drinks about 2 glasses of wine per week as a social activity. On a physical exam he is asked to take deep breaths during cardiac auscultation. The physician notices that the splitting of S2 decreases during inspiration. Which of the following is most consistent with this physical exam finding?", "options": {"A": "Asthma recurrence", "B": "Atrial septal defect", "C": "Left bundle branch block", "D": "Pulmonary stenosis"}, "answer": "Left bundle branch block", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 27-year-old black male presents to the emergency department with severe wheezing, which started an hour ago. He informs the doctor that he has had mild persistent asthma for the last 2 years and is on inhaled corticosteroids, and uses them regularly. He has not experienced asthma symptoms for the last 2 months and there is no history of non-compliance. He mentions that his present symptoms came on about 20 minutes after his last meal. When the doctor makes specific inquiries, he recollects items in his lunch, which included canned milk product, commercially available roasted peanuts, homemade celery salad, and wine. He also mentions that he took a tablet of acetaminophen immediately after the meal because his legs were aching since morning, which he attributes to his morning walk at 6 am the same day. He has never developed respiratory symptoms in response to milk protein, peanuts, or acetaminophen until now. Skin prick testing for food allergens, performed a month back, was negative for all the common food allergens, including milk and peanuts. Which of the following is the most likely trigger for the patient's current episode?", "options": {"A": "Ara-h-1 protein", "B": "Food additive", "C": "Acetaminophen", "D": "Exercise"}, "answer": "Food additive", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 42-year-old black male presents with acute onset jaundice. Past medical history is significant for COPD diagnosed 4 years ago, managed medically, and admission for acute pancreatitis 6 months ago. The male denies any history of smoking, alcohol use or recreational drugs. Which of the following is the most likely etiology of liver damage in this patient?", "options": {"A": "α1-antitrypsin (AAT) deficiency", "B": "Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency (G6PD deficiency)", "C": "Dubin–Johnson syndrome", "D": "Hepatitis C"}, "answer": "α1-antitrypsin (AAT) deficiency", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 47-year-old black male is brought to the emergency department 1 hour after his neighbor found them collapsed on his front porch in a pool of vomitus. On arrival, he is oriented only to self. His pulse is 103/min and respirations are 30/min. Neurologic examination shows muscle spasms in the arms and jaw. Serum studies show: Na+ 137 mEq/L Cl- 99 mEq/L HCO3- 8 mEq/L Osmolality 328 mOsm/kg The difference between the calculated and observed serum osmolality is 32 mOsm/kg. Urinalysis shows oxalate crystals. This male is most likely experiencing toxicity from which of the following substances?", "options": {"A": "Methanol", "B": "Ethylene glycol", "C": "Parathion", "D": "Aspirin"}, "answer": "Ethylene glycol", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 68-year-old black male presents to the emergency room with productive cough and fever. He has a chronic cough that has been getting progressively worse over the last 2 weeks. Last night he developed a fever and vomited. He smoked one pack of cigarettes per day for 40 years and recently quit. His past medical history includes COPD and his medications include ipratropium and fluticasone. On physical exam his temperature is 102.2°F (39°C), blood pressure is 131/78 mmHg, pulse is 110/min, respirations are 22/min, and oxygen saturation is 95% on room air. He has decreased breath sounds bilaterally with diffuse crackles. You obtain a sputum sample and identify an organism that grows selectively on medium containing factors V and X. Which of the following organisms is the most likely cause of this patient's symptoms?", "options": {"A": "Haemophilus influenzae", "B": "Streptococcus pneumoniae", "C": "Mycoplasma pneumoniae", "D": "Fusobacterium species"}, "answer": "Haemophilus influenzae", "answer_idx": "A", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 64-year-old black male with knee osteoarthritis comes to the physician for a follow-up examination. He reports significantly improved pain control since starting celecoxib 1 month ago. A history involving which of the following conditions is most likely to explain the administration of this drug instead of another nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug?", "options": {"A": "Reye syndrome", "B": "Sulfa drug allergy", "C": "Glanzmann thrombasthenia", "D": "Gout"}, "answer": "Glanzmann thrombasthenia", "answer_idx": "C", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 47-year-old black male presents to his ophthalmologist for abnormal vision. The male was discharged from the hospital 2 weeks ago after a motor vehicle accident where he was given 1L of blood. He also underwent several surgical procedures including enucleation of the right globe and exploratory abdominal laparotomy to stop internal bleeding. Currently, he states that he has noticed decreased vision in his left eye. The male has a past medical history of poorly controlled diabetes, asthma, and atopic dermatitis. His temperature is 98.9°F (37.2°C), blood pressure is 167/108 mmHg, pulse is 90/min, respirations are 14/min, and oxygen saturation is 97% on room air. Physical exam is notable for 20/200 vision in the patient's left eye, which is worse than usual. The patient's left eye appears red and irritated. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?", "options": {"A": "Anterior uveitis", "B": "Normal post-operative visual adaptations", "C": "Seasonal allergies", "D": "Sympathetic ophthalmia"}, "answer": "Sympathetic ophthalmia", "answer_idx": "D", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 41-year-old black male presents with progressive fatigue, pain in the front of the chest, and difficulty breathing with minimal exertion while trying to sleep. He reports having a flu-like illness consisting of fatigue, muscle pain, and cough 10 days ago that resolved spontaneously without seeking medical help. He has no past medical history. He does not smoke cigarettes or drink alcohol. His vital signs include a blood pressure of 100/70 mm Hg, a temperature of 37.5°C (99.5°F), and a regular radial pulse of 105/min. On physical examination, the male looks tired, the jugular venous pressure is elevated, pulmonary rales are present on both sides, and an S3 gallop is audible. His ECG shows nonspecific ST-segment and T-wave abnormalities. A 2-dimensional echocardiogram shows global left ventricular motion abnormalities and dilatation of the left ventricle. Troponin I and Creatine Kinase-MB are elevated. Which of the following is the most likely mechanism of the male illness?", "options": {"A": "Rupture of an atherosclerotic plaque in the coronary artery", "B": "Viral-mediated inflammation with local and systemic immunological activation", "C": "Infection of the endocardial surface of the heart with microembolization and immune complex deposition", "D": "Immune-mediated inflammation of the heart triggered by a preceding streptococcal infection"}, "answer": "Viral-mediated inflammation with local and systemic immunological activation", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
{"question": "A 57-year-old black male comes to the physician because of a 5-day history of fever, joint pain, malaise, and a diffuse rash. Two months ago, he was diagnosed with latent tuberculosis and the appropriate treatment was administered. Examination shows a scaly, maculopapular rash over the chest, arms, and back. Which of the following is the most likely explanation for this patient's current condition?", "options": {"A": "Decreased acetaldehyde dehydrogenase activity", "B": "Decreased acetyltransferase activity", "C": "Decreased cytochrome p450 activity", "D": "Decreased glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase activity"}, "answer": "Decreased acetyltransferase activity", "answer_idx": "B", "metamap_phrases": []}
